<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openshift on Nube</title>
    <link>/categories/openshift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openshift on Nube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Cesar Valdez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 14:30:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/openshift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Your Own Istio (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/post/prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 14:30:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/prometheus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some days ago, I was watching this video about Istio in Google I/O and while watching it, I started to think on how to do it or how they achieve this or that feature. So, as an excuse to learn how to build containers that collaborate with each other, I decided to replicate some of the functionalities I saw in that video for fun and at the same time to learn how I can encapsulate behaviour like I usually do with objects, but with containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Build Applications in OpenShift</title>
      <link>/post/buildconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 19:24:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/buildconfig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to discuss the different strategies for building our software in OpenShift. These strategies are useful if you need to solve any of the following problems:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting external images to Openshift</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-12-imagestream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-12-imagestream/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started First you need to have an Openshift installation on the cloud or in your machine, the second option is the easiest one thanks to the oc cluster up command, this will create a small local installation of openshift in your machine, if your are not familiar take a quick look at the documentation.
Creating a project Once oc cluster up finish you should have an Openshift installation up and ready in your local machine, now next step is to login in and create a project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>